Boys' Drama Series
They Were Eleven!
We will now begin the final test.
You ten have been selected from among 40,000 applicants, having passed several rounds of testing.
Each of you is likely among the top minds of your respective academies.
However,
what the Cosmo Academy seeks is not just intelligence,
but individuals who excel in every respect.
That spaceship
is the site of your final test.
What you have to do will become clear once you arrive.
Forward,
right turn!
March!
Halt!
Now, depart!
It's an old phrase, but...
With the development of antigravity,
space travel advanced remarkably, and in 200 years, Earth came to have 51 colony planets.
However, one after another, colonies desiring independence declared war on the Earth Federation.
While war between Earthlings continued across space,
the sudden discovery of aliens forced all Earthlings to unite.
400 years have passed since.
Earth joined the Interstellar Federation under the name Terra,
alongside three great nations—Rota, Segul, and Saba—and other smaller races.
Thus, peaceful coexistence between Earthlings and aliens was achieved.
And today marks yet another entrance exam day for the Cosmo Academy.
Hey!
The Chancellor said there would be ten of us!
What about it?
Look!
There’s an extra!
There are 11 of us!
Huh?
It’s true!
There are 11 of us!
There really are 11!
They Were Eleven!
Original Work
Moto Hagio
Screenplay
Mamoru Sasamoto
Music
Hirose Ryōhei
Performance
Ansanburu Sharuman: Ensemble Charman
No idea...
Wait, I don’t even know what I’m waiting for, I don’t know, I don’t.
?
Hey, whoever snuck in, come clean!
Who the hell are you?
Who sneaked in?
?
Chancellor,
give orders to the ten applicants.
This is serious!
What’s going on?
Someone has snuck onto the spacecraft with the applicants.
What?
Is that true?
Yes.
Please look at this.
It’s the message he left behind.
A final message?
Chancellor,
it seems the man who snuck in intends to die along with the applicants.
Who is he?
We don't know.
He just said he hates those trying to enter the academy and become future leaders.
Chancellor, it’s dangerous.
Let’s call them back right away.
No.
The test will proceed.
It’s a major incident,
but perhaps this way, we can conduct an even better test to suit our true objective.
Understand?
What Cosmo Academy seeks is individuals with sound judgment and action in any situation.
The final test will proceed as planned.
You...
?
This spaceship’s airlock
was rigged to automatically explode once sealed.
One blast every three minutes.
Whether we can stop it or not—that’s the test, huh?
So that’s what he meant by “you’ll find out once you get there.”
Applicants to Cosmo Academy,
You ten will now stay aboard this ship for 53 days as crew members.
There are not ten!
There are eleven!
This is a test of cooperation under the risk of being sent adrift.
Chancellor!
There’s one too many!
Can’t you hear us?!
If even one person fails, all ten will be disqualified.
?
Chancellor!
In the event of an emergency, press the emergency button.
All other contact will be impossible.
No good.
It’s over.
We will come to pick you up only if you press the emergency button , or if you stay alive for 53 days.
Now, we wish you luck.
Can’t they hear us? Damn it!
Hey.
What are we going to do?
The academy believes we’re ten.
It’s been a mess from the start.
So what do we do if there are eleven?
Do we hit the emergency button and all fail?
Huh?
Don’t joke around—stop it!
Own up, intruder.
Whoever's the 11th is, speak up now.
There's no point in arguing.
How about we go check out this spaceship?
We're gonna be living here for 53 days, after all.
Hey,
this door won't open.
That's weird.
There's not even a knob.
Step on the yellow line at your feet.
You sure know a lot about this. Huh!
That’s just—
?
Don’t worry, Frol.
This is an antibiotic plant.
It’s not gonna eat you.
Who said it was gonna eat me?
I was just a little surprised, okay?
Everyone, listen up.
Anyway, we’re isolated and have to spend 53 days inside this ship.
And with an 11th person we don’t even know.
So here’s my suggestion.
From now on, no one’s allowed to act on their own.
You're giving the orders now?
Obey the king, huh?
From now on, everyone must work in pairs.
Even entering a room, be in pairs.
But if you say that, someone's gonna be left out.
You'll get a room to yourself.
What?
I don’t need to explain why, do I?
You bastard, you think I’m a girl or something?!
I absolutely hate women.
Women are trash.
You bastard!
Frol
?
I wonder what kind of face I should make when things are strange.
Any thing is fine.
?
Please tell me.
How can you be so kind?
Any thing is fine.
?
Please tell me.
?!
It's fine, isn't it?
I found it in the living quarters.
It sounds good, right?
Stop, I said!
Come on, come on.
How about a drink?
It'll make you feel good,
and you'll forget all the bad things.
I told you to stop.
Who is it!
Who is the 11th person!
Please, identify yourself!
?
Well, well, I was thinking,
why don't we press the scramble button and have them come help us?
Damn it,
if you do that, everyone will fail.
But...
I can't stand it anymore.
Press the scramble button!
What will happen now?
What will become of us from now on?
Is there anyone with advanced knowledge?
I want to repair the computer.
Do you understand?
There's a repair manual.
If we can fix the computer, we might be able to communicate with each planet
and possibly uncover the identity of the 11th person.
Just press that button over there.
Ganga
Tada is suspicious after all.
He knows too much about this ship.
I saw it.
I saw Ganga tell Tada to press the button.
At that time, Tada must have pressed a different button.
Ah, the one who would be troubled if the computer is fixed is the 11th person.
How is Ganga?
The operation was a success.
Tada, delivered amazing work.
Thank you, Tada.
But that doesn't mean your cleared of suspicion Tada.
What does that mean?
You've been on this ship before, haven't you?
What?
Then why do you know so much about this ship?
It's a misunderstanding. I don't know this ship.
It's my feeling.
Raise your hand if you think he's suspicious.
What are you saying?
Tada tried hard to help Ganga.
I oppose.
Let's vote.
Those finding Tada suspicious.
Those opposed.
Tada is not suspicious.
5 to 4.
By majority vote, we will confine Tada.
I oppose.
Ganga you have to rest.
?
5 to 5.
It's a tie.
Ganga, thank you.
What are you saying?
Wasn't it you who helped me?
But I was surprised. Your blood is...
It's fine.
Frol.
You wanted to say that my blood was green, right?
That's correct.
I am a type of cyborg from the Tredorega people.
Created through the Chlorella cultivation method.
A cyborg?
The species of my planet have very short lifespans.
They can't escape the planetary-wide food disease,
and everyone dies around the age of 30.
So, as a way to live longer,
I consented to becoming a cyborg.
I am the test subject for that.
Then, it's really good that you were saved.
Yes, I am truly grateful from the bottom of my heart.
However,
becoming a cyborg costs money.
So, I want to enroll in the Cosmo Academy to think of ways to make money.
So that all the Tredorega people can live longer.
I see.
Tada,
why do you want to enter Cosmo Academy?
I did it for my planet and for myself.
Tada
But, for some reason...
My planet's species have very few people.
Because of that, we are always oppressed and suppressed by the surrounding planets,
and some species, like the Sibelius, are on the verge of extinction.
That's why medicine advanced so quickly on my planet.
?
So, we want to research ways to live and prosper with younger species.
Everyone has various dreams.
From each distant galaxy,
we come with dreams and hopes.
Ten people of about the same age.
No,
eleven people.
I see.
But, what kind of dream does someone with eternal life have?
The eleventh person?
?
Is that person someone who has neither dreams nor a future?
Frol,
what is your dream?
Me?
I wonder if I can become a man or a woman.
What?
Nothing.
It's nothing.
Hey.
Frol is an amphibian and is neither male nor female until their secondary growth period.
On Frol's planet, Benede, men are the leaders and women work, and one cannot become a man
unless they are in the first phase.
As the youngest child, if Frol passes the Cosmo Academy entrance exam,
they are promised to become a male leader.
You.
Frol,
you're really a woman.
You're a woman, right?
Damn you,
I wanted to see it.
What the hell?
What are you doing, acting like a woman? Damn it.
?
You bastard.
Let go of me, you.
?
What’s going on?
Everyone, listen to me.
I was told that if I pass the Cosmo Academy entrance exam,
I can become a man.
I was told I could become a man and a leader.
So I absolutely have to pass this test.
Please understand.
Calm down, Frol.
Shut up.
Don't treat me gently like I'm a woman.
I'm a man.
I'm going to become a man.
Um,
I know this is sudden, but...
What's up, Choco?
Don't you hear something weird?
Hmm?
?
Let's talk about it later.
Why do you need an explanation?
Someday, we'll do something. What? A quest or something else. What happened?
What!?
What the hell.
Do I know this manager?
Seriously?
Yeah, it’s worse than that.
According to my calculations, this spaceship is flying toward the sun at an incredible speed.
What?
What are we going to do?
At this rate, the temperature will rise by 3 to 5 degrees per day.
Soon, the inside of the ship will become like a steam bath,
then a hell of intense heat, and then we'll crash into the sun.
Is that true, doctor?
Is it time for the scramble button?
Cut the jokes. I can't afford to fail.
So, does that mean Frol will roast alive?
Don't get ahead of yourself, Sunny.
And then, the electric star revived.
?
Everyone,
what’s going on?
It's the heat
Its growing because the temperature went up.
This is going to turn into a jungle soon.
?
This isn't the place for that.
If the ship's  temperature rises,
it will continue to grow,
and then...
?
Electric star.
Crystal.
Delsekihan disease.
Delsekihan disease?
It’s a disease.
A virus outbreak. And...
?
Tada!
Do you know something?
Confess!
So you’re the 11th one after all!
Tada!
Pull yourself together!
Are you ready?
Yes.
Good, place him here.
Yes
Hey, let him lie down nearby.
?
That suspicious guy can stay there.
Tada, are you really the 11th one?
Tada!
Scary!
Help me! I'm scared.
Leave it to me!
Tada, lift your head up!
It was you who snuck in, wasn’t it? You’re the 11th one!
No!
I am...
No, that doesn't matter.
Hurry and press the scramble button!
Everyone’s going to die!
Tada!
What are you saying?
Scary!
Help me! It’s scary!
Tada...
Frol, let go of him!
There’s no need to hurt  him!
No!
I’m not leaving Tada...
I care about Tada.
Even if Tada is the 11th one,
I...
Frol,
would you rather become a woman or die?
Tada.
Listen to me!
When I saw that electric cart,
I finally remembered.
Everyone,
I was on this spaceship when I was a child!
So it was true!
You were hiding it, Tada.
You just forgot about the mouth side!
That's right!
I can't believe that I was a baby at that time.
Then why did you suddenly remember?
It was that electric cart.
Tada...
?
Just like now,
that electric cart revived and the virus came from the crystals.
?
Destruction of the body, spots.
Loud sounds.
Extreme paralysis.
There was no vaccine.
There was a shortage of preventive vaccines.
?
So, my people,
thousands of them...
?
Extreme paralysis.
No vaccine.
?
Keep spreading the virus!
And kill them!
?
For a lifetime, until death, I did it all!
They were taken by the poison children,
made to work until death!
Stretch, stretch, stretch.
Stretch, stretch.
Amazon.
What are you doing here?
What is it?
Is the wound okay now?
What did you just say?
I think you were laughing loudly. Final.
Amazon.
What are you?
Shut up.
What were you saying? It's not like you.
Wait.
Amazon.
?
Ganga
Frol
?
Tada
What are you doing?
Look.
There are bombs planted on this ship.
One exploded at the beginning, and there are 119 left.
So what?
I'm gathering these bombs on the roof of the living quarters and I will explode them.
The rocket's trajectory might change.
What are you talking about?
If you do that, the entire spaceship might blow up.
But if we don't,
the tower reproduction will continue to grow.
How about pressing the scramble button and having a rescue ship come?
We can't do that!
Such a dishonorable act.
Dishonorable?
Is entering university and becoming a leader such an honorable thing?
It's not honorable!
Our dreams and future are at stake here.
For the sake of our dreams and future,
I would risk my life without hesitation.
Those with dreams,
those with a future, are truly happy, right?
What did you say?
How is it, king? My idea?
Alright, let's try it.
We'll take a chance and gather all the explosives inside the ship.
If we’re lucky, the trajectory should change.
Hey, hold that down for me.
Alright!
Frol!
Tada!
Foolish people.
Are dreams and the future really such important, precious things?
But, if we lost two people,
will everyone else just be considered failures?
If we can’t all return  together.
Tada
Frol
Frol.
For that time, we can call each other like this until we die.
Tada.
Tada,
what happened?
Won’t you say my name?
I don’t want to do this to a woman,
but please forgive me.
Frol.
I’m glad.
Tada!
?
Everyone, stay safe.
With me here,
it’s exactly 10 people.
Make sure to enter Cosmo Academy safely.
My dream,
my future.
Now I finally understand
why the population of my planet is so small.
Ganga!
Tada, I’m glad.
?
Thank you, King.
You’re the one who gave Ganga a long lifeline.
If even one of us is missing, everyone will fail.
Alright,
I’m hitting the explosive switch.
Ready?
?
Tada
Frol!
It’s nothing.
Medicine, medicine.
Stay strong.
Frol,
you have a high fever.
I told you, it’s nothing.
High fever.
Red spots.
Orocan?
Terze Cambion?
No, it’s not that.
I just caught a little cold.
Look!
The red spots are showing.
It’s not a problem.
Frol, what about you?
I’m sorry.
When I was surrounded by the Tutsan,
Frol came to help me.
I see, Ganga.
You didn’t get infected because you’re a cyborg.
I’m the one with Terze Cambion?
You’re kidding, right?
Frol.
What are we going to do?
There’s no vaccine.
But if we leave her like this, what happens to Frol?
Tada!
You really like the scramble button.
Are you really going to make me do this?
Sweat. I can’t let Frol die.
Eight days left.
Eight days, should be enough.
Alright. Over here.
?
I see.
You don’t know if you’re siding with Tada or with Yōsei, do you?
Look at Tada!
You all want to be leaders.
You don’t care what happens to any of these lives, as long as you get to stand above everyone else.
How noble.
You’re all such splendid leaders.
Amazon!
What about you?
A slave planet on the frontier.
A slave from Cygnus.
?
You think of us as animals on a raft.
It’s the planet of telepaths.
Using those telepaths,
you make us work for you, right?
?
So, you’re the eleventh one.
So, what will you do?
Is Frol’s life more important?
Or is honor
more important than life?
Oh, great leaders.
Everyone.
You can press the button, right?
Alright, I’ll press it.
There’s no need to give up yet.
In eight days, we’ll descend.
If you press it now, all the hard work of the past 45 days will be for nothing.
Shut up!
Wait a minute.
Stop it.
For my sake.
Just for me.
Frol.
If I’m going to die anyway,
I want to die as a man.
Frol.
It’s fine if you become a woman.
Then, you can be my leading lady
and marry me.
Tada.
Press the scramble button.
King.
?
Thank you.
For the first time, I realize there is something more important than honor—trust in others.
That’s the strength to believe in others.
?
You all passed.
You managed to endure for 45 days.
The examinees from last year
pressed the scramble button within 20 days.
And on top of that, you faced the unexpected accident of an 11th person.
Congratulations.
Congrats. We did it.
Where are you going Amazon Kaanais?
To space prison.
Oh.
Don’t you want to enter Cosmo Academy?
Huh?
Didn’t you also endure for 45 days?
Amazon Kaanais.
After graduating from the Academy,
please dedicate your efforts to improving the universe.
Congratulations, Amazon.
I’m glad, Amazon
Amazon.
Amazon, ?.
?
I’m glad,
Tada
?
Frol
Tada
?
Translated by ChatGPT
Edited by Paul Geromini