41st year of the Showa era, 9th Month (September 1966)
Pencil sharpeners!
Okajima
Oh... so cool.
Good, good, good, good...!
Wow...
Whoa!
After all, it's better than using normal one to shave.
Electricity is cooler!
Ah….
"The waves slurp
Separate it."
"Sweet and snug the clouds"
"Where is Gourd Island going?
Where is it taking us?"
Taeko!
What do you think a pencil is for?
You must not use the electric pencil sharpener anymore.
2nd year of the Reiwa era, 9th month (September 2020)
Wow!
Haa...
Grandma, is this a pencil sharpener?
Oh, how nostalgic!
That's right! A pencil sharpener.
Can this be used?
You want to try it?
Okay...
Yeah?
It moves!
Wow... Amazing!
This is Grandma's too
Mizuki's mother also used it.
Huh?
Is it that old?
Mizuki!
Don't carry your own luggage!
Yes.
Only Yesterday
Nice!
Let's eat!
Delicious!
Ah, that's good!
I used a hint of grandfather's secret sauce.
From now on, can I eat it every day?
Of course.
And when my grandpa is discharged from the hospital
You can eat something even more delicious.
Yes!
But isn't the taste a bit strong?
What? Is that so?
Your tongue is numb because your eating while drinking milk.
I've been drinking milk with my meals for decades.
I am not going to stop now.
How long has mom drunk milk with dinner?
That's right.
She has been like this since she was a child.
Been like this...
First of all,
It was Mom who kept insisting, 'Drink milk, drink milk,' to the point of being annoying.
I want you to drink a lot of milk and grow up big. It's a pure parent's love, you know.
I've grown too much, though.
For Showa-era moms
I want you to reflect on it.
There are many people like me, who grew tall and have complex feelings about it.
But it's a lie that drinking milk will make you grow taller.
Oh, is that so?
So it's not my fault.
Hmm!
See, this is also very flavorful.
Mizuki... Is your mom's cooking always mild in flavor?
Hmm...
I don't know because it's always just microwaved.
What are you doing?
Don't rely on microwaves, make it properly.
If Dad heard that, he would be sad.
I've just been busy lately, so we've had a lot of microwave meals.
Even when you're not busy, we still have a lot of microwave meals.
Microwave, microwave, microwave. Stop saying 'microwave' over and over!
From now on, no matter how busy you are, make dinner at least twice a week.
I'll do it even if you don't tell me. See? I even made dinner today.
Ah.
What you made is moving-in soba.
Soba is just boiled.
Soba, at least, isn't a microwave meal, huh?
Be quiet! Geez...
Mizuki's school play?
Yeah. I heard they might not do it this year because of COVID, but...
You know, the sports day got canceled too, so...
At the very least, they decided to hold the school play, just on a smaller scale.
Oh, Mizuki, that's great!
But... I only have a small part.
That won't do! You can't have that attitude.
Listen, you have to treasure every single moment!
Living on stage is what's important.
Grandma, what are you talking about?
Acting!
When I was on stage, that was what mattered the most.
As an actress, that's very important.
But Grandma, you weren't an actress.
41st year of the Showa era, 9th Month (September 1966)
What?
You're doing Kobutori Jii-san for the play?
Yeah.
What role are you playing, Taeko?
An old woman? Oh, a demon?
Village Child 1.
Just village child 1?
But you do have lines.
Yeah.
Is that so?
Yes.
Yeah, she has the most lines among the villagers.
Ah, a crow...
What?
What's about a crow?
That's the line.
Ah, sorry, sorry.
(Clears throat)
Behold, the crows fly home. First one...
One bird!
Behold, the crows fly home.
First one...
You said you had the most lines, but it's just one!
Huh?
The village scene is only the one part Taeko just did?
That was it?
Yeah.
But that doesn't really have much to do with the story of Kobutori Jii-san.
Behold, the crows fly home.
First one...
Josai Ward Municipal Koshin Elementary School
Yes!
Well then I'll start with Yamada-kun.
Good...
(Looking out) Ah, it's another good day.
Hey, let's try doing it a little more energetically.
Good?
Hey, what does it say when we come out?
"Appear while playing."
What are we going to play?
Hmm...
Hmm... anything is fine.
That's not good!
Let's think about it properly.
Ah, what about hopscotch?
If it's hopscotch or something
You can come out right away, right?
Okajima-san!
When people are practicing let's look on quietly.
Yes.
Behold, the crows fly home.
Look up there!
First one...
There's only one line, but that girl keeps on.
How much practice is enough?
Behold, the crows fly home.
You're practicing at school, right?
First one...
That was all they did the the first half today.
They weren't even able to practice up to her scene.
Look up there!
Behold, the crows fly home.
Somehow, I've started to feel sorry for my younger sister...
First one...
Look up there!
Wow!
Yay.
Look up there!
Behold, the crows fly home.
One bird!
Two birds.
Three birds.
Four birds!
Wow!
Goodbye Mr. Crow.
Take care.
Wow!
Yes.
Yes!
Very well done!
However, Mr. Okajima
Only say the lines written in the script, Okay?
Yes!
Well then let's move on.
You can go back now..
Yes.
Next up… Yamada-kun.
The bump on your cheek
brings happiness to everyone.
Dance, dance have fun.
Only say the lines written in the script.
Everyone say it louder this time.
Did she really say that?
No wonder
I thought I couldn't hear the lines today.
Geez she was just too enthusiastic.
Even though she only had one line.
That's right.
Besides no one is even watching the villager scenes anyway.
But they said thanks to that, they understood.
Huh?
What do you mean by "understood"?
They figured out how to approach their role.
Ah. I see….
The Grateful Crane
Fifth Grade, Class Four.
Story of Kobutori Jii-san ("Grandpa with a Lump")
Fifth Grade, Class Five.
Next up, Class 5's "Grandpa with a Lump".
Somehow I'm getting nervous..
She only has one line anyway..
Oh, stop it.
Ah… Ahh, what a wonderful day.
Oh… Dear…
So… Well then I shall
Go… to the mountain… and… set out.
Grandpa… Pa… Please take care!
Ha… Yes!
Waa!
Wow!
She came out.
Look up there!
She's in front.
Behold, the crows fly home.
One bird!
She pointed.
Two birds.
Three birds!
Four birds!
Yay!
She waved her hand….
Taeko-chan was so good!
I'm so surprised.
What children's theater group is she in?
None at all.
If she's that good will she be an actress in the future?
No, no.
Ah, but really, what a relief!
So that's the direction for the role....
How's Natsuki doing?
She's doing fine, but work seems tough.
You know, since early spring.
"Her salary went down, but
the workload increased," she said.
That's worrying.
Things should get a bit easier for her
since she's moving into our place.
She'll save on rent too.
She have anyone special?
She might be dating someone,
but I don't think she's considering remarriage.
Mizuki is there too.
I see….
Oh, right, speaking of which—
Mizuki's school
decided to hold the school play as planned.
Oh, Mizuki is in it too?
Seems like it! So, you know
I gave her some acting tips.
Mizuki must have been so annoyed.
How rude!
Even if I say so myself
For a fifth-grade girl, I had
genius-level acting techniques. Me!
Yeah, yeah. I've heard it a million times.
Ah... If only Dad hadn't said no.
I definitely would've become a great actress.
I just know it.
At the very least,
I would have surpassed Keiko Matsuzaka!
Hey, hey,
don't underestimate Keiko Matsuzaka.
She's a huge actress.
Ahahaha! You're right. Hehe.
Since Natsuki and the others moved in,
it feels lively.
Yeah.
You know, having the sound of people's footsteps
in the house is really nice.
And somehow it makes me reminisce.
Back when I was Mizuki's age.
Ah, I had so many happy memories
back then.
Hey Taeko…
From now on, do what makes you happy.
Huh? What's with that, all of a sudden?
Well... I've been thinking lately.
I feel like I've been a burden on you.
When I was 40, I suddenly said I wanted to open a Western-style restaurant
and quit my job….
Even though we live close by,
I barely got to see my grandkids.
Well, now you can make up for it.
Working non-stop from morning till night.
That's why, Taeko,
in the life ahead
I want you to find
new joys and happiness.
Thank you.
But for now,
instead of me,
please take care of your own health.
Yes, yes, thank you.
Second Life for the Senior Generation
Let's find goals, dreams, and things we like.
A new life…
Second Life for the Senior Generation
Josai Ward Municipal Koshin Elementary School
Who is this?
Once more!
Very good!
Yes, next.
“This is Mark Smith.”
Repeat after me.
This is Mark Smith.
OK! Once more.
OK! Very good.
Alright! Woo.
Stop it!
Hey give it back!
It's mine!
Throw it quickly!
Pass it! Pass it!
Hey what are you doing!
Hey!
Hey let's go….
Class is starting. Hurry up, hurry up.
That was close….
Are you okay?
Sawada-kun, change your clothes like a man, confidently
Right?
It's nothing to be embarrassed about.
Energy energy!
Right?
Energy! It's P.E. P.E.
Come on, let's hurry!
Oh class is starting.
Hurry.
Good work today.
Good job.
Sugimoto-san.
Yes.
Can you go on a business trip Saturday, October 17th?
Ah yes….
Thank you.
10:00 Mizuki School Arts Festival
Excuse me, Chief, about that day….
What's wrong?
19:21 - Thank you! Sorry.
Arrived at the station. What should we eat?
19:43 I'll arrive in 2 minutes. I feel like having meat today
Want to get food today?
Sorry, I have to make dinner today.
What should I make for dinner?
Isn't that Natsuki-chan?!
Ah, hello.
I heard you're going to live with Taeko-san?
Whoa, word travels fast!
Taeko-san is really happy.
She said she's excited to live with her grandchild.
And are you excited, Natsuki-chan?
Oh, absolutely not!
She's always nagging me about everything.
I'm already exhausted.
What's wrong?
Oh, sweet and sour pork?
Looks delicious.
Finishing touch… There!
Ah! Wait!
Why are you adding pineapple?!
Why? It's standard!
It makes the meat tender and adds sweetness...
You already know I hate pineapple.
You know that, right?!
Huh? Really?
It's fine, just pick it out.
I only hate pineapple,
but I love sweet and sour pork.
Geez! You're such a troublesome kid!
I'd like to see your parents!
The mirror's in the bathroom!
41st year of the Showa era, 12th month (December 1966)
Oh! That's right!
Next week is my birthday party!
Thanks! I'm looking forward to it!
Toko-chan, I'll bring pineapple!
Pineapple?
That is what I told Dad when I was invited.
Dad?
D- D-Daddy?
Who's that?
My father!
Your father?
Mihoko-chan used to live in America.
America?
Yeah! And in America,
people call their father by their first name.
So, it's like calling him Taeko or Yaeko.
So you know in America they eat pineapples.
Raw?
Yeah!
Wow.
Not just bananas.
Pineapples, real ones. Not canned.
I'm home.
Ah Daddy's home.
Welcome back.
Oh Taeko, you're still up.
Yeah!
Here bananas for you.
Oh! Welcome back Kenzo.
Kenzo?
Hey Kenzo
buy a pineapple tomorrow.
Why are you calling me by my first name?
She learned something weird again.
Come on, pineapple!
Right? Not canned.
A real pineapple.
Ah, that kind of thing isn't sold in Japan.
It is!
The next day
Dad where did you buy this?
At a Ginza department store.
Oh it must've been expensive.
Taeko the Knife.
Is this right?
Yeah.
I'll put it here.
Here we go.
Okay.
How do we cut this?
Hey Nanako.
Be careful when cutting.
Can I have this?
Yeah.
Ah Wow! It smells so good!
Smells good.
Taeko, let me smell.
Yeah!
Smells good!
A bit sour smell.
Mom too Mom too…
Oh!
Let's eat!
Let's eat.
It's hard.
Not at all sweet.
It tastes different from canned ones.
Sour.
Not that great.
I'll give it to Taeko.
Me too.
I'm gonna take a bath.
Taeko, you don't have to force yourself to eat it.
Yeah.
You'll get a stomachache.
Mom, tea.
Ah Okay.
This is boring.
Oh dear, I've been asked out on a date.
Delicious…
What should I do?
Is it still too soon?
But….
Feels happy,
but also a bit scary
Beating heart, beating heart
I'm off!
Yeah.
I'm going to visit Dad sometime soon.
Ah, you should do that.
How is Dad's health?
He's stable.
But you know he's been saying some weak-hearted things.
"From now on do what makes you happy."
"In the life ahead I hope you find
new joys and pleasures", he said.
Isn't that Dad reflecting in his own way?
The shop was so busy he probably feels he troubled you.
I've never once thought of it as trouble.
I'm truly glad I married your father.
Ah, is this bragging?
In my life those words would never come out.
That's because you're a single mother, right?
Mom could you stop twisting the knife so hard in the morning?
For my life ahead…
What should I do?
Once COVID settles down, how about taking a trip?
Hey.
How about Hokkaido, where Aunt Yaeko lives?
It's been a while. You should go visit her.
She'd probably find it a hassle.
"Why are you coming all the way from Tokyo?"
I see…
The other day Nana-neechan told me the same thing on the phone.
Her husband is really uptight.
Then why don't you go on a solo hot spring trip?
Second Life
A solo hot spring trip would just be lonely.
<Lots of results for what to do as a retiree>
Senior Limited, Stage Audition - Theater Company Nenrinza
Theater Company Nenrinza
Inaugural Performance
○ Theater Company Nenrinza Inaugural Performance
○ The performance that was canceled in spring will now be be performed this autumn!
○ Shakespeare for those 60 years old and over!!! Actors wanted!! Beginners welcome!!!
○ Up-and-coming director, Shinnosuke Sakaguchi, challenges the "possibilities of an elderly theater company"
Huh?
○ The performance that was canceled in spring will now be be performed this autumn!
○ Shakespeare for those 60 years old and over!!! Actors wanted!! Beginners welcome!!!
○ Up-and-coming director, Shinnosuke Sakaguchi, challenges the "possibilities of an elderly theater company"
What is this…
Wait…
No way!
Taeko-san…
Hey Taeko-san.
Huh? Ah What?
Listen to this!
This morning I got into a fight with my dumb son.
He just won't study at all, so I told him,
“Enough already! I'm throwing away all your games!”, and then he said
“Go ahead. I'll just buy them again with my New Year's money next year.”
Seriously I just want to smack him!
Kids have their own strengths and weaknesses, you know.
Take math for me, I was so terrible at it I hated studying.
41st year of the Showa era, 9th Month (September 1966)
Uh… Um… You see… Um…
Before this test, um… we had art class.
And then, um.
we did blow painting.
Blow painting?
Y- Yeah!
Um… we dripped paint onto paper, and
then blew on it to make patterns.
And then?
A- And then…
My head… started hurting.
See, look.
I blew so much.
So that's why you got this score?
Y- Yeah… that's right!
Honestly, this is such a mess.
So, do you at least know the correct answers for the ones you got wrong?
Huh?
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
What?
What is this!? What happened!?
Ah… Please explain it to her. She doesn't seem to get it at all.
Huh? Huh? But, but…
No matter what, how could this happen!?
Huh? Taeko? Are you feeling okay in the head?
That's why I said, you would explain it to her.
If she did it normally, there's no way she'd get a score like this!?
That's because Taeko isn't normal!
You got a headache from blow painting, right? Right, Taeko?
Just flip the numerator and denominator and multiply, that's all.
That's how they taught you at school, right?
So why did you get it wrong?
Dividing fractions by fractions… what does that even mean?
Huh?
I mean, uh…
Dividing two-thirds of an apple by one-fourth means...
How many apples per person?
If you divide two-thirds of an apple among four people.
So, per person, simplifying two-twelfths
makes one-sixth of an apple.
That's multiplication!
Eh!?
Hey, if we're multiplying, why does the number get smaller?
You're too fixated on apples, that's why you don't get it.
For multiplication, keep the top and bottom.
For division, flip them, that's all you need to remember!
Maybe Taeko should get an IQ test. Wouldn't that be a good idea?
Hmm… but when she entered school, they said she was normal.
Maybe she just got dumber.
When Taeko was a baby, she fell from the second floor, right?
Yeah, yeah! In a baby walker!
Back then, I thought she was a goner.
Maybe that's catching up now…
But if you divide two-thirds of an apple
by one-fourth…
If you divide two-thirds among four people,
how much does each person get?
I really didn't get it back then.
That whole math concept.
Taeko-san,
what was your childhood dream?
Huh? Why?
Well…
I was just curious what a girl who was so bad at math dreamed of becoming.
Huh? What's with that?
Basic Information
Self-Promotion / Personal Appeal: "Ever since my elementary school days, when I experienced acting in a school play, I've longed to stand on the stage again someday. I've turned 64 this year, my children are settled, and my husband tells me to do what I like. I would like to give it my all. I will do my best."
Handling of Personal Information: <boilerplate legalese>
Agreement and Submission
No way,
I can't say it.
It's too embarrassing now… Ugh…
Grandma, I'm home!
Wah!
Main Cast Audition Application Form
Submission Completed
Oh...
I sent it....
Oh... I sent it!
Huh? What happened?
What should I do...
No! I don't want this...
No way.
No wait come back...
Hey come back!
Come back!
No no... No way!
Grandma!?
Grandma, come back!
Grandma!
Grandma you really wanted to be an actress.
But Grandma's father said no.
Why?
Back then it was different from now.
Women got married and staying at home was considered happiness.
That's how it was.
I see.
Hey, what kind of person was Grandma's father?
41st year of the Showa era, 5th Month (May 1966)
The House of Representatives on the 14th… The Japan Socialist Party….
Taeko!
Honestly, Dad is way too soft on you, Taeko!
Weren't we supposed to only get dolls on birthdays or for Christmas!?
Right? Isn't that so, Dad?
Is that true, Ta-bo?
Well, big sis Yaeko got a furisode even though it wasn't her coming-of-age ceremony.
Even then it wasn't for her ceremony!
Unlike you, we don't get lots of little things bought for us.
Instead, we get something big once in a while.
Right?
Exactly!
That furisode will eventually belong to Taeko, so it's fine, isn't it?
All I ever get is hand-me-downs!
Some kids can't even get hand-me-downs, you know.
Exactly. Exactly
Then hurry up and give me that enamel bag already!
Oh? I haven't given it to you yet?
Just give something so childish to Taeko already.
A secondhand handbag…
I don't want it….
Ah, is that so.
Fine then I won't give it to you.
Is it raining?
Oh… It's raining.
I hate this kind of bag.
Come on Taeko, hurry up.
Hurry up slowpoke.
I don't have a handbag!
Come on Yae-chan,
lend her that enamel bag.
Come on hurry up.
Here.
Ouch….
Alright let's go.
I'm not going.
Oh really!
Let's go Mother.
What?
Ta-bo's not going?
Not going.
Alright then let's go.
Are you sure?
I'll go too!
Barefoot…!
Father!
Scary!
Normally it's not like that.
Running out barefoot was a shameful and disgraceful act that made him angry.
Even if they're selfish, a father wants them to grow up beautifully.
Well that's just Grandma's guess though.
Mizuki
do you want to see your father?
No.
Then…
have you ever wanted to?
I don't know.
I see.
Hey why don't you come over?
Huh?
Why would it come to that?
It's fine because I like you.
That's not the issue here.
Hey come on.
Hey Shunsuke….
Yeah?
You have no intention to marry, right?
Huh?
Why so suddenly?
If it's just for fun then stop it.
Just because I have a child doesn't mean I'm not thinking about remarriage.
You know, even I...
I'm thinking that someday it'll happen again.
Yeah….
Nenrinza Company Inaugural Performance
Audition Venue
Waiting Room
It's just like a hospital waiting room, isn't it?
That's true.
Ah, Nice to meet you I'm Kida.
My name is Sugimoto.
Pleased to meet you.
Next person please come forward.
Mr. Katsuya Ishikawa.
Yes!
Ms. Sachiyo Mizumoto.
Yes.
Ms. Taeko Sugimoto.
Yes!
Mr. Hiroki Yamada.
Please this way.
It really does feel like a hospital….
Take care.
Ah I'm off then.
(Whiteboard) Nenrinza Company
Inaugural Performance: "A Midsummer Night's Dream"
Audition
Scheduled Performance Dates: Saturday, October 22nd
The play we'll be performing this time is Shakespeare's, "A Midsummer Night's Dream."
It's a comedy centered around marriage between men and women, but I also see it as a tragedy.
The story takes place in a forest near Athens.
There, nobles, craftsmen, and
fairies living in the forest appear.
Now then let's start reading the lines.
Okay, Mr. Katsuya Ishikawa.
Yes!
Please begin.
Seems like there's no choice but to rest.
Thank you very much.
Uh… Sugimoto Taeko-san.
Yes!
Please go ahead.
Ah…
Ahh I'm exhausted!
But this is the saddest I've ever felt.
How cruel…
The mist soaks me through.
The thorns scratch me…
I can't crawl or move forward anymore.
I guess I'll just have to rest….
Like this until dawn
Thank you very much.
Uh… Yamada Hiroki-san.
Yes!
Please go ahead.
Yes.
Yes, Sugimoto speaking.
Yes…
Really!?
Wow, what should I do?!
Yes…
Yes!
Thank you very much!
Excuse me!
Eh?
Was that about the audition?
I got in!
Wow… Grandma did it!
I did it!
You did it! You did it!
I'm home.
You did it!
I'm home!
What are you two so happy about?
Grandma passed the audition.
Huh?
Audition?
What is this about?
Grandma is going to perform on stage!
What!?
Mizuki is in the school play
Grandma is also in a play!
Yeah! Let's do our best in practice together!
Let's do our best!
No way?
Seriously?
Seriously!
Mizuki.
Hmm?
On the day of the school play
Mom might have to work….
I might not be able to watch it…
That's okay, right?
Oh, I see.
Well…
You know... I've finally gotten busy recently..
Sorry.
Yeah
it's okay.
List of the cast and characters for Shakespeare's "A Midsummer Night's Dream
Looking forward to working with you all!
Nice to meet you.
I am Taeko Sugimoto, playing the role of Hermia.
Um… Please feel free to call me Taeko or Tae-chan.
I will give it my all
to avoid causing trouble for everyone.
I look forward to working with you!
It is a pleasure to make your acquaintance.
Suu suu suu… Suu shuus… Hmm?
"Duke Theseus."
Thi… Theseus….
Duke Theseus!
Ahh, Egeus, huh?
Did something…
happen?
Egeus.
Yes.
You're being called.
Ah… Sorry.
Is it… my line?
Um… Where was I?
Ah, Here!
I… I have an important announcement.
What is it?
What happened!?
Huh!
Uh… Actually…
I must file a complaint against my own daughter, Hermia.
What!?
Hermia
Hermia...
You don't need to react there.
Ah sorry.
Okay. Um, for now Let's stick to what's written in the script.
Okay.
Yes yes!
Egeus,
Ah okay.
please continue.
Step forward Demetrius.
Haha!
Wait, wait um Shibui-san?
Your role, Shibui-san is Lysander.
Huh?
The one just called was Demetrius.
Ah... oh that's me.
That's right it's you, Kida-san.
My apologies.
I'll step forward.
Um… this man
is the one I have consented to give my daughter to.
Step forward Lysander.
This is
the man who has secretly confused my daughter's heart.
You have sent love songs to my daughter and delivered tokens of your love, haven't you?
Please! Forgive me. I....
Too fast.
Huh?
Too fast Too fast.
Hermia's line is still two pages ahead.
Ah I'm sorry.
I just couldn't hold it in anymore.
No, no please hold it in.
There's an order to follow.
I'm sorry.
Taeko-san,
are you okay?
I'll say it once more okay? Let's stick to what is written in the script.
Huh... Okay! I'm sorry!
Yes.
Well then uhm page four....
Only say the lines that are written in the script.
"You have sent love songs to my daughter" from there please go ahead.
Yes.
Ugh! This is so frustrating!
Even at 10 years old, I was told the same thing.
I haven't grown at all, it's actually pretty funny.
Rehearsals for a play move along so fast.
Well, even if they do move fast, in the end, it's just a bunch of amateurs, so we can't do much.
Rehearsals are progressing, but so is our forgetfulness.
What does that mean!?
But you know, in times like these,
I'm really grateful to be able to do this.
Even if I embarrass myself, it helps me stay positive…
Just thinking that makes me happy.
I know it's dramatic!
Taeko-san, that's wonderful.
You sound like you're in love.
41st year of the Showa era, 5th Month (May 1966)
Excuse me,
is there someone named Okajima here?
Ah, that person over there.
Hirota-kun from my class,
said he likes
Okajima-san!
That was surprising seriously!
Yeah, totally seriously!
Huh? Is that true?
Excuse me,
who is Hirota-kun?
Oh he's from Class 5.
Hiro!
Hiro! They're calling you.
Yes that's me.
Okajima-san from Class 5 said, "I don't know how to respond to something like that."
Huh?
That's what Okajima-san said.
Yeah exactly.
Huh… I didn't say anything though.
Hiro you said you like that girl from Class 5, Okajima, didn't you?
So I just told her for you.
What….
Ah! Taeko-chan!
No running in the hallway. Okay?
I told Hirota-kun for you.
What!?
I properly told him, okay?
Good for you Taeko-chan.
Now you can relax.
Yeah….
What! Hirota from Class 4 likes Okajima!?
Hirota is amazing.
He's the ace.
We are going to lose in the finals for sure.
No way.
Baseball?
Oh the one after school this Saturday…?
That one you think you'll lose?
Oh Hirota!
Let's play tag!
Sounds good!
Ready… Rock-paper-scissors, shoot!
See ya!
Let's go!
five, four, three, two, one, zero!
Starting now, the match between Class 5-4 and 5-5 begins.
Bow!
Please take care of us!
Let's go!
Hiro do your best!
Go Go Hi Ro Ta!
Okajima is watching you!
Play ball!
Nice one Hiro!
Amazing! Amazing!
Taeko-chan
If you cheer for Class four, I won't forgive you.
N-no… I wouldn't do that.
Go Go Class Five!
Alright!
Ah….
Game set. Five to three. Class four wins!
Thank you very much!
It's Sue's fault!
Sue's.
That's right!
Why me? You guys don't even understand.
I know the rules of baseball at least.
Alright everyone did great!
The teacher will treat everyone to ice cream!
Um….
Rainy days,
cloudy days,
or sunny days…
Which do you like the most?
C...
Cloudy….
Me too.
That was close….
Whoa, that was close... I almost ran into Sawada in the bathroom.
That guy is still as creepy as ever.
Seriously, I'm so glad I didn't turn out like him.
Are you wasting your time?
Are you wasting it?
You have to save time.
Ready….
You must not!
Okaaay
OK! Applause!
Good, good Perfect Perfect!
Keep it up!
Umm Alright next is…
Sugimoto-san and Sawada-kun.
Okay come on up.
Okay okay okay okay okay.
Sawada-kun! You're a guy,
so stand up straight, stand tall!
Straight! Got it?
Look everyone's laughing at you.
Alright?
Okay so you two umm…
hold hands and say the lines.
Alright ready?
Here we go.
Ready...
Go!
Look, look.
Who's that kid?
I don't know.
Maybe a girl.
Yes.
OK!
Applause!
Mom, I heard your stage rehearsals have started?
I'm really so fed up.
Dad, say something too.
Let Mom do whatever she wants.
But I never thought she'd become an actress.
Seriously.
A second life as an actress? Never heard of that before.
I've accepted this illness.
Until I die I'll have to live with it and deal with it.
That's why I want Mom to enjoy herself.
Yeah…
Well fine
She can do whatever she wants.
There you go again being jealous.
I'm not jealous.
Everyone knows that Natsuki is trying hard.
But you're not the only one who has it tough.
I know that already.
Mom has always done her job as your mother.
I said I know….
Yeah.
You don't have to force yourself to be friends with me.
I know everyone finds me creepy.
I'm not forcing myself.
And I don't think you're creepy.
I'm already used to it.
Used to what?
Being talked about.
Always?
That… how should I put it…
Like being a girl…?
Yeah.
I hate men.
So I hate my dad too.
Dad always looks at me with such disgust.
I see….
That sucks for you.
It can't be helped.
So I'm used to it now.
Sawada-kun your condition is a mental illness, right?
So… I think people who talk badly about you are awful.
You're pretty awful too, you know.
Huh?
What the hell do you mean by illness?
Don't talk like you understand!
Chief.
About the upcoming business trip. Let me go after all.
Huh? But your daughter….
I asked my mother to take care of her school event.
So it's fine.
But… I already asked Hirooka-san.
What?
Ah okay. I'll go then.
Ah… but….
It's fine.
We don't have kids, so we're more flexible.
Enjoy your daughter's school play.
Work's over. What are you doing today?
Sorry, I have plans.
“Please, forgive me.
Please, Duke. Please, forgive me.
I do not know, what kind of power has emboldened me like this.
And yet, to express my thoughts
before everyone here
might be…
against a maiden's modesty maybe…”.
I'm home.
Ah!
Welcome back!
You're late.
You must be hungry.
Let's eat.
No need.
I'm not hungry.
Mi-zu-ki….
"But, please.
Please. Duke, please tell me.
If I refuse to marry Demetrius,
what grave punishment shall I receive?"
I'm home.
Welcome back.
Hey…
Hey.
Mizuki is acting strange.
Strange?
Even after coming back from cram school she said she wasn't hungry
and went straight to her room without eating dinner.
I see.
Hey why don't you check on her?
She'll be fine.
She'll come down when she's hungry.
But she came home an hour later than usual.
Maybe she was playing with friends?
It didn't seem like that.
You're her mother, you should….
I told you, she'll be fine!
What's with you….
I'm just… tired from work.
What the….
Just because you're tired, does that mean you can just neglect your daughter?
I'm not neglecting her.
Yes, you are!
As a mother, it's only natural to worry about your daughter, right?
Just because I'm a mother, it's "natural"…?
I can't handle being relied on so much.
Of course, she relies on you!
If a child can't rely on their parents, who else can they rely on?!
The times are different from when you were a mother.
Back then, having a place to live was normal, having a family was normal.
Food is just there, as if it's the most normal thing.
Being told to be a mother as if it's a given.
Worrying about your daughter has nothing to do with the times, right?
Then mom,
aren't you worried about dad?
Huh?
You barely take care of him.
And at your age, you still want to be on stage?
Isn't that failing as a wife?!
I do take care of him.
Oh, sure you do.
I go to the hospital as much as I can and do what I can.
I'm doing what I can too.
Listen,
Mizuki has no father.
Why are you saying that now?
So what if she doesn't have a father?
What does that even mean?
You have to be both a mother
and a father.
That's what it means to be a single parent, right?
You chose that, didn't you?
Yes, I did!
I chose it because I thought it was the best!
Then take proper responsibility!
I am taking responsibility!
Am I really such a bad mother?
No
I'm not saying that, but….
Is it so bad to make something in the microwave?
Other than work do I have to be with my child all the time?
Am I not allowed to think about anything but my child?
I'm so tired…
I can't be a perfect parent….
No….
What's wrong?
Mom I thought you came home. So I just came downstairs.
Welcome home.
I'm home.
Did you finish your homework?
Yeah, it's done.
I see.
Grandma I'm hungry.
Huh… Really?
Then let's get something ready.
Mom, you should eat with us too.
Yeah…
I'm hungry too.
This minced meat cutlet is delicious.
I'm glad.
Grandma how's your practice going?
Everyone's struggling to memorize their lines.
There are only two weeks left so we have to work hard.
I see.
Mizuki?
How's your school play practice going?
Yeah well….
Did something happen?
Is practice not going well?
No it's not that…
The boy sitting next to me told me not to act like I know everything.
Huh?
I thought I was the one who understood him the most.
Well…
people's feelings are complicated.
I'm looking forward to the school play.
Huh?
Mom aren't you working?
Yeah. It's fine now.
Thank you!
Yeah.
Let's eat.
Just like you said,
people's feelings are complicated.
What? Where did that come from?
Well you see,
I had a similar experience like Mizuki did.
Really?
There was a transfer student named Abe-kun.
41st year of the Showa era, 6th Month (June 1966)
Reduce 12/8 to a simple fraction by using common factors.
Alright then
Suzuki-kun, Nishino-san, Tsuda-kun,
come to the front and give it a try.
Hey
let me see your homework.
N-no… I don't want to….
Why not?! Just show me!
Ah….
Abe-kun!
Okajima-san!
You know, Abe-kun's family is definitely poor.
Stop saying things like that.
But but his hands are all dirty and his clothes are super filthy.
Besides Abe-kun is bad at studying
and he picks his nose….
Hey stop it already. I'm preparing dinner.
Ugh… I hate sitting next to him. I wish summer break would come so we can change seats.
Tickle time.
One more time. One more time.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Abe-kun's shirt
that was Tanaka-kun's shirt in 4th grade.
No way!
Oh you know...
Abe-kun when he's on duck duty
he takes the duck feed bread home with him.
What? Really?
Yeah, really.
I never knew.
Ah…
What I just said is a total secret okay?
Yeah.
It's a secret.
Hey!
I dumped the water for you.
Oh wait I was on duck duty.
The spot Abe-kun touched
Gotta wipe it again.
Ew….
I wonder if Abe-kun is taking home the duck bread again today?
What!?
No way!
Due to family circumstances
Abe-kun is transferring schools suddenly.
Abe-kun take care.
Okay.
Let's have everyone shake hands one by one to say goodbye.
Ehh….
Abe-kun let's start from over there.
I'm not shaking hands with you.
Abe-kun knew about it….
Gross.
Hey! Don't do something so dirty!
Ouch….
Here.
In our class,
more than anyone else…
The one who hated Abe-kun the most
was me….
Well then.
I'll take a bath first.
Okay.
Natsuki.
About earlier
I'm sorry.
I went too far.
Me too…
Sorry.
Yeah…
You've been working hard.
It's fine, don't worry.
Talking about it made me feel a bit better….
I'm looking forward to your play too.
Oh
I never thought I'd hear that from you.
Thank you.
But in return, don't embarrass us.
Don't underestimate my acting.
Please Duke
I beg your forgiveness.
What kind of power has made me so bold, I do not know.
Again to speak my thoughts before everyone
may be against a maiden's modesty.
But please Duke.
Teach me, I beg you.
If I refuse to marry Demetrius what will be
the severe punishment
I will receive?
Okay then uh, next
Sugimoto and Sawada's scene let's go.
Yes.
Ready…
Go!
Look, look.
Who is that kid?
I don't know.
Is it a girl?
OK!
Amazing I think you have improved. Really good.
OK
Work's over. What are you doing today?
Sorry, I have plans
We haven't talked much lately, have we?
Was what I said last time too heavy? (lol)
Well…
I guess that's it.
Hide - Delete
Achaa!
Senpai
what happened?
Don't mind me.
It's nothing.
Let's stick it.
Where is good?
Hmm…
Diagonally?
Tilt it a little?
One patch of grass is enough for two pillows.
One heart. One bed.
Two chests, but one true love.
No Lysander.
Why not?
Ah… Eek!
Hermia it's fine just for tonight.
Lysander please listen to me.
Don't come so close move farther away…
No no…
Ah! Get away!
Lysander one more time.
Hermia it's fine just for tonight.
Get away!
One more time! One more time! One more time!
Huh?
Mizuki, I haven't seen you for a while.
Haven't you gotten taller?
A little bit.
I just talked with the doctor…
They said I'll be discharged soon.
What?!
Really?
Yay!
With this I can finally see Mom's big moment.
Huh?
The play?
You're going to watch it?
Don't do that you're still recovering.
It's fine.
I need to move a bit to regain my strength.
Dad
is looking forward to seeing the great actress perform.
Hey who exactly is this great actress?
Where can I meet her?
Huh? Right in front of you. Look right in front of you.
Huh? Where, where? Where, where?
Oh no! I'm going to be late for practice!
I don't have time to be chatting nonsense with you.
So mean!
Alright I'm heading off first. Bye.
Ah.
Okay.
Geez, honestly.
Grandma seems to be having fun every day.
Yeah.
Ah
I have to go to rehearsal for the school play.
Hey once you're discharged again,
can we eat Grandpa's food too?
Of course.
I'll make plenty for you.
Yeah.
Sorry I'm late….
What happened?
Did someone pass away?
Taeko-san don't say such ominous things!
But they're crying….
The performance is getting canceled.
What!?
What do you mean?
The theater we rented
went bankrupt….
Huh!?
Last night we got a call from the theater's lawyer.
No way… But suddenly telling us now….
Yeah I'm just as shocked.
This morning we went to the theater too,
but it was completely deserted.
Is there nothing we can do anymore?
But, we've paid the rental fee, right?
Yes.
Not in full, but….
Partially
the impact of COVID played a role too.
And now, at this point….
Oh no….
41st year of the Showa era, 10th Month (October 1966)
Hyokkori hyotan-jima
"The waves go splash splash splash Pushing through the waves.”
“Splash Splash Splash”
“Swiftly passing through the clouds.”
“Swish Swish Swish”
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'm Ito from Nishi University's drama club.
Huh? You mean Taeko?
Yes. We'd love to have her join us.
Oh, but…
We need an actor for a play. We were hoping Taeko could take the role….
We'd really love for her to participate. Would she be willing to join?
Hey, hey.
What were you guys talking about? Was it about a play?
Some university drama club members want Taeko to act in their play.
"Taeko really shined in the school play."
And? And?
They bowed their heads and asked me to let you join.
Yay!
That's amazing, Taeko.
Arifune Transport Minister Replaced
But I really think it's amazing. To be offered such an opportunity.
Well, I guess everyone has at least one talent.
Oh, Taeko is good at writing, too.
Maybe Taeko has more talent in that than in math.
Really really?
I played the old man in "Tongue-Cut Sparrow", but
I never got any offers.
Right right?
So…
What are you gonna do?
Are you going?
This could be the start of a career as a child actress.
Hey you should join Takarazuka!
Yeah!
If you start training now, you might get in.
Eh! Really? Eek!
What should I do?!
No way!
Show business is out of the question.
Come on… 'show business' is an overstatement.
But still….
No!
Dinner!
Yes….
She's a shy and
introverted girl….
I'm very sorry.
I see.
Understood.
Well then, excuse me.
I wanted to do it… I really wanted to do it….
I wanted to do it….
I really wanted to do it.
Grandma I'm home!
Grandma…
Ah wash my hands!
What's wrong? Why are you in such a rush?
Grandma!
Today's practice with everyone was so much fun!
I felt like I understood something.
Really? What did you understand?
Like our feelings became one.
Before, I never felt that way.
But today I did.
Really!?
Everyone cherished each and every moment!
And then somehow I felt like we were all connected.
Grandma do you understand?
This feeling!
Mizuki.
Living on stage is what matters
You said that!
Yeah I did!
And today I finally got it!
I see that's great.
I understand.
You know, Grandma too
has been training all this time
And once again I realized how important that is.
Right?
Thank you Grandma!
Alright!
I've decided!
Huh?
What is it?
I won't give up. Not over something like this.
There's no way I can give up now.
Mizuki,
thank you. For telling me!
Grandma will never give up!
I won't give up!
I'm getting nervous.
Still Mom was so unlucky. Shakespeare.
Well it can't be helped.
Life goes on. There are many things in life.
To live is to face trials.
Well Mom's dream didn't come true,
But at least you get to see your grandchild's play.
Isn't that happiness?
Wait a second.
Who said I gave up?
Huh?
But the play got canceled….
This time.
It was just canceled this time.
What do you mean?
I took another audition.
What!?
...And I passed!
No way!
Next is Chekhov. Amazing, right?
Unbelievable….
Ah! Mizuki!
Do your best!
Hey stop it. She only has one line.
Cherish every moment!
Yeah!
Ah thanks.
Translation: Google Translate and ChatGPT
Editing: Paul Geromini
Only Yesterday